Alright, so now it's
time for the ultimate
presenting hack. I guarantee
no matter who you
are, this is the
best way to present
a video. And I
know it because when
I used to make
videos for businesses, we
specialised in getting people
to present on camera
no matter who they
were. And for years,
we ignored this. It
was dumb. Which meant
one short 60 second
video would sometimes take
an hour for people
to present and they'd
still come across as
a bit stale and
scared and bored like
this. And I'm not
kidding you, sometimes they
would cry because they
found it so hard.
I made a girl
cry once. I didn't
know what to do.
I panicked. Made it
worse. Anyway, when we
made the change, people
who had never been
on camera before were
knocking videos out in
10 minutes following everything
I've just taught you.
Now, this mega tip
does have an initial
learning curve and people
will struggle with it
and give in because
it's hard. But you
will get past it
after some practice. And
what will happen is
a 10 minute script
will take you 12
to 15 minutes to
film. But not only
that, and I tested
this so many times,
it will seriously, and
I mean seriously, speed
up your editing too.
In fact, I made
a video without it
to see how much
of a difference this
made and it took
me 40 minutes to
film due to the
mistakes I kept making
and 90 minutes to
edit the narrative and
cut all the rubbish
that got in the
way versus 5 minutes
in the edit and
12 minutes to film.
And everyone who has
taken my advice on
this has messaged me
to say, Ed, this
is a game changer.
Please don't write this
off. It's the only
presenting hack. It's called
a teleprompter. I have
used it on every
video I've ever made
for years. I put
my script on a
free app called Parrot.
I put my phone
in it. And then
I present. I'm using
one right now. That's
what this little remote
is. I'm just winding
it back and forwards.
Not gonna hide it.
Can't be bothered. You
shouldn't be worried about
hiding it either. Too
many people stick their
noses up and they
say, I don't need
one, I can just
riff off of bullet
points. And then they
wonder why their channel
won't grow because riffing
means waffle, it means
no storytelling, it means
no structure, it means
repetition, it means no
metaphor. It also means
way more mistakes and
way more time wasted.
A well -written script
presented on one of
these bad boys means
you don't have to
think whilst you present.
You can just focus
all your energy on
it. On your camera
presence and your body
language and your emphasis.
And you can worry
about nothing that comes
out of your mouth.
So now I'm going
to show you how
to present using one
of these to look
authentic. Oh, and by
the way, 90 %
of the top creators
in the info space
are using these. Honestly,
do not kid yourself
into thinking you're better
off without. I'd fight
you to the death
over this. Oh look,
my confidence score just
shot up. Anyway, the
first thing you need
to do is load
your script into a
free app called Parrot.
There's other apps, but
I use this one.
You then play about
with the text size
and the speed of
the scroll. And then
once you've set it
up, the key is
to try and not
present your script in
one go. What I
actually usually do is
set it up slightly
slower and then I'll
present a few paragraphs.
And then I'll probably
stop and let it
catch up a bit.
What this does, it
enables me to keep
my energy up because
trying to present with
high energy for 10
minutes straight is exhausting.
And you probably won't
be able to do
it at the start.
I still struggle after
doing this for like
eight years. I then
load that into the
edit, cut out all
the gaps and mistakes
or use recut, which
is basically software that
will do that for
you. And usually in
10 to 15 minutes,
I have edited the
entire script. I've edited
the entire narrative of
my video. Now to
enable this to be
really slick, I space
out the lines in
my script like this
so it's easy to
read and there are
lots of natural catch
up points. Then I
present a few lines,
stop, present a few
more and so on.
Now the remote I
showed you earlier links
to the app. So
what you can do
is push the button,
stop, start it and
control the pace. And
some people even found
a way to make
a foot remote so
they don't have to
have this in shot.
They can just tap
it with their foot.
I really just don't
care if it's in
shot though. And then
when you make a
mistake, you simply rewind
and you say the
line again. And then
you're done. When you
make a mistake, you
simply rewind and you
say the line again.
See what I did
there? Teleprompters do come
with a problem though.
And it's one I
had for a very
long time and it
made me look crazy.
I got tons of
negative comments below my
videos because of it.
But the solution is
really simple. So I'm
going to walk you
through it now. So
when people use teleprompters,
they often say they
don't like it because
they don't look natural.
And the reason for
that is because they
just stare at the
screen a ton. And
imagine if someone just
sat there chatting to
you, intensely looking into
your eyes the whole
time. It would be
so weird. So all
you do is you
look away from the
camera. Sometimes kind of
like you're thinking about
what you have to
say. And then you
look back. If you
look at any of
my videos and I
don't look at the
camera, that is 100
% intentional. And in
my head, in that
exact moment, I'm going,
Ed, look away. I'm
literally doing it right
now. So look to
the side, have a
think about what you're
saying, and then come
back to the prompter.
And then the next
thing you need to
remember to do is
blink. I used to
get so many comments
like, this dude just
presented for 20 minutes
and didn't blink once.
When you're really trying
to focus hard and
read the words, it'll
happen. Now, these small
things, they add up
to make it easier.
They add up to
make the viewer feel
uncomfortable. And that is
going to knock your
credibility and not build
trust. And we have
to build a lot
of that as you're
going to find out
in the whole of
this course. Okay, so
the next thing I
need to know is
just don't buy a
big teleprompter. The bigger
they are, the more
eye movement you'll have.
And when people spot
your eyes darting about
all over the place,
they will never unspot
it. If you use
an iPad instead of
a phone, just make
sure you put the
text only the width
of the lens because
your eye movement will
be so small, people
can't see it. And
that's it. I'll leave
some links to products
I recommend. But if
you're interested, I recommend
you check out my
blog. It's really important
you get one because
script writing is the
number one skill for
you to get good
at. It's where the
retention is. And when
you follow the system
I'll teach you, it's
going to change your
life, hopefully. Just stick
to the system and
it will. And script
writing is the number
one skill because you're
not just learning how
to write videos. You're
learning how to grow
businesses, make sales, blow
up on other social
media platforms. And riffing
from bullet points won't
allow you to build
that critical still and
it will really, really,
really slow you down.
By the way, if
you were thinking, who
on earth was that
guy presenting the video?
That was me. Without
these on, look. Same
guy. That was back
before I didn't have
eye strain 24 -7
from constantly rewriting this
program.
Anyway, before we move
on to filming your
demo script, later in
the advanced modules, there
is a full course
James and I made
on how to build
a home studio, how
to light it properly,
and how to level
up your video quality.
But I do not
want you worrying about
buying cameras and mics
and lights. The only
reason I'd recommend you
ever watch that module
is if your video
is not good enough.
If your video quality
is so bad, it's
going to wreck your
credibility or create some
mismatch with your viewers'
expectations for your niche,
which I'll teach you
more about in the
coming modules. Basically, if
you are filming on
an old rubbish phone
or webcam and you
don't own a light
or a mic, that
is you. Otherwise, we
want to focus your
energy on the stuff
that's going to actually
grow the business, which
is strategy writing, launching
videos, and getting onto
funnels. So please don't
prioritize that quite yet.
Members, if you have
any questions about Kit,
ask James in the
Discord. He has every
answer. Okay, so now
move on to the
next video where you're
going to look at
the title and go,
Oh, it's about presenting.
I'll skip that. How
do I know? Well,
because I can see
the data of what
you guys are doing
and everyone skips this
one. And then members
in particular come into
the support chat and
ask me tons of
questions that this video
answers all of the
time. To which my
response will be, go
and watch the f***ing
video.
But also, ignoring this
video is a minus
100x move because what
I'm going to teach
you in it is
one of the ways
I make videos that
turn viewers away from
me. And that's probably
played the most important
part in getting people
to trust me for
years.
So skip it if
you like failing and
watch it if you
don't. How's that for
an end screen baby?